A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Oral Histories, RG 13 FA119
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, Oral Histories, RG 13
1960-1974
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA119
11.2 Cubic Feet 29 letter document boxes and 1 half-letter box
Scope and Contents
The Foundation's archives include:
Projects General Correspondence Administration, Program and Policy China Medical Board International Health Board/Division Field Offices Treasurer's Office Comptroller Personnel Fellowships Information Services Diaries Oral Histories Counsel Secretary Minutes and Officers Actions Dockets Declinations (100F) Non-textual Materials Communications Office
Conditions Governing Access
Officers' oral histories are open for research subject to any written conditions on access established by the subject of the oral history or his/her designated representative. If no written guidelines exist, an oral history is available for research 20 years from the date of the interview.
Arrangement
Primarily alphabetically by surname.
Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations; Life sciences; Philanthropy -- United States; Charities; Agriculture; Philanthropy; Public health; Medical education; Public policy; Oral histories
- J. Curtis Dixon, 1967; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box; 1 copy, 3 volumes, 535 pages, no attachments
  Biographical / Historical
  Dixon, born in 1894, was State Agent for the GEB, and Director of the Southern Education Foundation.
  Scope and Contents
  Interviewed by Mary R. Hawkins, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, July 17, 1967-July 21, 1967. Atlanta, Georgia.
  - Volume 1, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Volume 2, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Volume 3, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- John B. Grant, 1960-1961; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes; 1 copy, 7 volumes, 1238 pages, appendix "Personal History" 32 pages
  Grant was Associate Director for Medical Education and Public Health. He was born in 1890 and died in 1962.
  Interviewed by Dr. Saul Benison, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, October 25, 1960-1961. New York.
  - Volume 1, 1960-1961 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Volume 2, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Volume 3, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Volume 4, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Volume 5, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Volume 6, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Volume 7, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Alan Gregg, 1956-1957; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  Gregg was Director for Medical Sciences and Vice-President. He was born in 1890 and died in 1957.
  - Alan Gregg, 1956-1957; 1 copy, 1 volume, 247 pages, appendices i-xii "Legal Medicine" (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Edited by Saul Benison, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, 1956-1957. New York.
- J. George Harrar, 1978-1979; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
  Harrar was born in 1906 and died in 1982.
  - J. George Harrar, 1978-1979; 2 copies. (Box 4, Folder 2, Box 5, Folder 1)
    RF Agriculture Program, President. Interviewed by J. William Hess and Dorothy Parker, April 27, 1978 - January 8, 1979.
- Victor G. Heiser, 1970; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  Heiser was Director for the East for the IHD. He was born in 1873 and died in 1972.
  - Victor G. Heiser, 1970; 1 copy, 1 volume, 202 pages, no attachments (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Interviewed by Mary Boccaccio, The Rockefeller Foundation, May 18, 1970 - June 11, 1970. New York.
- Lindsley F. Kimball, 1980; 0.19 Cubic Feet 1 half-letter document box
  - Oral History Final Form, March 10, 1980 - April 9, 1980 (Box 2B)
- John Marshall, 1972-1974; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes; 1 copy, 14 folders, 1053 pages, attachments included
  RF Humanities Program. Interviewed by Pauline Madow, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, December 11, 1972 through January 30, 1974. Connecticut.
  Marshall was born in 1903 and died in 1980.
  - Interviews 1 and 2, 1972-1974; Pages 1-80. (Box 1A, Folder 1)
  - Interviews 3 and 4, 1972-1974; Pages 81-150. (Box 1A, Folder 2)
  - Interviews 5 and 6, 1972-1974; Pages 151-207. (Box 1A, Folder 3)
  - Interviews 7 and 8, 1972-1974; Pages 208-282. (Box 1A, Folder 4)
  - Interviews 9 and 10, 1972-1974; Pages 283-362. (Box 1A, Folder 5)
  - Interviews 11 and 12, 1972-1974; Pages 363-443. (Box 1A, Folder 6)
  - Interviews 13 and 14, 1972-1974; Pages 444-541. (Box 1A, Folder 7)
  - Interviews 15 and 16, 1972-1974; Pages 542-645. (Box 1A, Folder 8)
  - Interviews 17 and 18, 1972-1974; Pages 646-754. (Box 2A, Folder 9)
  - Interviews 19 and 20, 1972-1974; Pages 755-859. (Box 2A, Folder 10)
  - Interview 21, 1972-1974; Pages 860-955. (Box 2A, Folder 11)
  - Interviews 22 and 23, 1972-1974; Pages 956-1053. (Box 2A, Folder 12)
  - Supplemental Material - St. John Perse, 1972-1974 (Box 2A, Folder 13)
- Flora M. Rhind, 1968-1969; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes; 1 copy, 5 volumes, 1530 pages, appendices A-K
  Secretary, RF and GEB. Rhind was born in 1904 and died in 1985.
  Interviewed by Isabel Grossner, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, February 2, 1968-June 19, 1969. New York.
  - Volume 1, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Volume 2, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Volume 3, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Volume 4, 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Volume 5, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Appendices A-K, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Elvin C. Stakman, 1970; 1.14 Cubic Feet 3 letter document boxes; 1 copy, 9 volumes, 1687 pages, no attachments
  RF Agriculture Consultant. Stakman was born in 1885 and died in 1979.
  Interviewed by Pauline Madow, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, 1970. New York.
  - Volume 1, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Volume 2, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Volume 3, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Volume 4, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Volume 5, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Volume 6, 1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Volume 7, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Volume 8, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Volume 9, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Robert Briggs Watson, 1967-1968; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box; 1 copy, 3 volumes, 378 pages
  Watson was Associate Director for Medical and Natural Sciences. He was born in 1903 and died in 1978.
  Interviewed by Paul R. Hopper, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University. May 4, 1967-September 10, 1968. Chapel Hill, North Carolina.
  - Volume 1, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Volume 2, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Volume 3, 1967-1968 (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Benjamin E. Washburn, 1970; 0.38 Cubic Feet 1 letter document box
  Washburn, Director of the IHB, was born in 1885 and died in 1979.
  - Benjamin E. Washburn, 1970; 1 copy, 1 volume, 156 pages (Box 12, Folder 4)
    Interviewed by Mary Boccaccio, The Rockefeller Foundation, September 14, 1970. Rutherfordton, North Carolina.
- Warren Weaver, 1961; 0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes; 1 copy, 4 volumes, 783 pages
  Weaver was Director for Natural Sciences and Vice President. He was born in 1894 and died in 1978.
  Interviewed by Barbara Land, Oral History Research Office, Columbia University, March 15-June 28, 1961. New York.
  - Volume 1, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Volume 2, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Volume 3, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Volume 4, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 2)
- Rockefeller Foundation Program in Agriculture, 1961-1967; 4.94 Cubic Feet 13 letter document boxes
  Arrangement
  Arranged by surname of officer.
  - Doris Barnes, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 30 pages, no attachments (Box 15, Folder 1-2)
    Doris Halberg Barnes was the wife of Douglas Barnes. She died in 1984.
    Interviewed by William C. Cobb, October 14, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
  - Douglas Barnes, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 26 pages, no attachments (Box 15, Folder 3-4)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, October 14, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Barnes was born in 1922 and died in 2010.
  - Lynn Bates, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 47 pages, 7 pages of abstracts bound in (Box 15, Folder 5-6)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, January 3, 1967. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Bates was born in 1940 and died in 2021.
  - Norman E. Borlaug, 1967; 1 copy, 1 volume, 348 pages, no attachments (Box 15, Folder 7)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, June 13, 1967 - June 14, 1967. New York.
    Borlaug was born in 1914 and died in 2009.
  - Richard Bradfield, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 50 pages, no attachments (Box 15, Folder 8-9)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, November 30, 1966. New York.
    Bradfield was born in 1896 and died in 1981.
  - Jose Guevara Calderon, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 30 pages, no attachments (Box 16, Folder 1-2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, October 10, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Guevara Calderon was born in 1919.
  - Pedro Reyes Casteneda, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 14 pages, no attachments (Box 16, Folder 3-4)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, January 17, 1967. Monterrey, Mexico.
    Reyes Castaneda was born in 1923 and died in 2011.
  - Robert F. Chandler, Jr., 1966-1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 94 pages, no attachments (Box 16, Folder 5-6)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, July 29, 1966 and January 25, 1967. New York.
    Chandler was born in 1907 and died in 1999.
  - Alejandro Ortega Corona, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 74 pages, no attachments (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, January 4 and 6, 1967. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Ortega Corona was born in 1931 and passed away in 2014.
  - Thore Denward, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 14 pages, no attachments (Box 16, Folder 9-10)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, July 7, 1966. New York.
    Denward was born in 1924.
  - Nicolas Sanchez Duron, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 20 pages, no attachments (Box 16, Folder 11-12)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, October 11, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Sanchez Duron was born in 1923.
  - Gabino De Alba Flores, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 14 pages, no attachments (Box 16, Folder 13-14)
    Alba Flores was born in 1925.
  - John W. Gibler, 1967; 1 copy, 1 volume, 70 pages, no attachments (Box 16, Folder 15)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, May 1, 1967. New Y ork.
    Gibler was born in 1920 and died in 2006.
  - Ulysses J. Grant, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 43 pages, no attachments (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, April 13, 1967. New York.
    Grant was born in 1920 and died in 1987.
  - Leonel Robles Gutierrez, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 20 pages, no attachments (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
    Robles Gutierrez was born in 1919.
  - J. George Harrar, 1961-1962; 1 copy, 1 volume, 193 pages, no attachments (Box 17, Folder 5)
    RF Agriculture Program, President. Interviewed by Mrs. Barbara Land, April 1961- February 1962. Revised 1969. New York.
  - Elmer C. Johnson, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 82 pages, no attachments (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, June 24, 1966 and October 17, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Johnson was born in 1920.
  - Charles F. Krull, 1966; 1 copy, 1 volume, 59 pages, no attachments (Box 17, Folder 8)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, June 29 and 30, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Krull was born in 1933 and died in 1998.
  - Reggie J. Laird, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 71 pages, no attachments (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, June 22, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Laird was born in 1920 and passed away February 27, 2014.
  - Arthur David Leach, Jr., 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 51 pages, "Developing Two Agricultural Experiment Stations in Chile," reprinted from AGRICULTURAL ENGINEERING, Nov. 1966, bound in. (Box 18, Folder 1-2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by W. C. Cobb, March 8, 1967. New York.
    Leach was born in 1930.
  - John H. Lonnquist, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 37 pages, no attachments (Box 18, Folder 3-4)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, October 4, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Lonnquist was born in 1916 and died in 1982.
  - Neil B. MacLellan, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 43 pages, no attachments (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, October 7, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    MacLellan was born in 1920 and passed away November 22, 2013.
  - Paul Mangelsdorf, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 142 pages, no attachments (Box 18, Folder 7-8)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, November 16, 1966 and December 19, 1966. Cambridge, Massachusetts.
    Mangelsdorf was born in 1899 and died in 1989.
  - Leonard A. Manuel, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 45 pages, no attachments (Box 18, Folder 9-10)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, June 13, 1966. New York.
    Manuel was born in 1905 and died in 1972.
  - John J. McKelvey, Jr., 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 93 pages, no attachments (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, March 2-3, 1967. New York.
    McKelvey was born in 1917 and died in 2020.
  - Harry M. Miller, Jr., 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 102 pages, no attachments (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, February 14, 1967 and May 12, 1967. New York.
    Miller was born in 1895 and died in 1980.
  - William I. Myers, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 115 pages, no attachments (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, December 8, 1966. New York.
    Myers was born in 1911 and died in 1970.
  - Delbert Myren, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 73 pages, no attachments (Box 19, Folder 7-8)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, June 23, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Myren was born in 1925 and died in 2012.
  - John Strong Niederhauser, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 257 pages, "Potato Research in the Soviet Union, a confidential report to the Trustees," bound in, 25 pp. with 2 pp. graphs and 14 pp. photographs, dated December, 1960. (Box 20, Folder 1-2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, October 20-21, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Niederhauser was born in 1916 and died in 2005.
  - Robert D. Osler, 1966-1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 80 pages, no attachments (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, December 23, 1966 and January 3, 1967. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Osler was born in 1924 and died in 1999.
  - Dorothy Parker, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 150 pages, appendix: "The Rockefeller Foundation Library Program for Agriculture, 1960" (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, April 4-14, 1967. New York.
    Parker was born in 1910 and died in 1999.
  - Jesse P. Perry, Jr., 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 287 pages, 16 pages of photographs with key bound in (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, February 14, 1967-March 3, 1967. New York.
    Perry was born in 1913.
  - John A. Pino, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 211 pages, no attachments (Box 22, Folder 1-2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, May 29, 1967-June 9, 1967. New York.
    Pino was born in 1923.
  - John B. Pitner, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 115 pages, no attachments (Box 22, Folder 3-4)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, June 15, 1967. Florence, South Carolina.
    Pitner was born in 1917 and died in 2010.
  - Ralph W. Richardson, Jr., 1966-1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 287 pages, no attachments (Box 23, Folder 1-2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, December 5, 1966-February 23, 1967. New York.
    Richardson was born in 1918 and died in 2010.
  - Lewis M. Roberts, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 116 pages, no attachments (Box 23, Folder 3-4)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, August 22-25, 1966. New York.
    Roberts was born in 1915 and died in 1999.
  - Dieter Enkerlin Schallenmueller, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 23 pages, no attachments (Box 23, Folder 5-6)
    Enkerlin Schallenmueller was born in 1926 and died in 1995.
  - Jose Rodriguez Vallejo, 1966; 1 copy, 1 volume, 19 pages, no attachments (Box 24, Folder 1)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, October 13, 1966. Mexico City.
    Rodriguez Vallejo was born in 1920.
  - Elvin C. Stakman, 1966-1967; 1 copy, 1 volume, 253 pages, no attachments (Box 24, Folder 2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, June 1966 and May 1967. Mexico City, Mexico and New York, N.Y.
    Stakman was born in 1885 and died in 1979.
  - Warren Weaver, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 20 pages, no attachments (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, July 13, 1966. New York.
    Weaver was born in 1894 and died in 1978.
  - Edwin J. Wellhausen, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 365 pages, no attachments (Box 25, Folder 1-2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, June 28, 1966-October 19, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Wellhausen was born in 1907 and died in 2001.
  - Vivian S. Wellhausen, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 38 pages, appendix 1 p. (Box 25, Folder 3-4)
    Interviewed by William C. Cobb, October 3, 1966. Mexico City, Mexico.
    Wellhausen was the wife of Edwin J. Wellhausen. She was born in 1909.
  - Kenneth Wernimont, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 93 pages, appendix 44 p. - Confidential Report for the Benefit of the Trustees #197, April 1959, "Rockefeller Foundation Scholarships and the Mexican Revolution in Agricultural Science." (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, March 22, 1967-May 8, 1967. New York.
    Wernimont was born in 1909 and died in 1991.
  - Sterling Wortman, 1966; 2 copies, 1 volume, 105 pages, no attachments (Box 26, Folder 3-4)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, August 2-4, 1966. New York.
    Wortman was born in 1923 and died in 1981.
  - Joe D. Wray, 1967; 2 copies, 1 volume, 89 pages, no attachments (Box 26, Folder 5-6)
    RF Agriculture Program. Interviewed by William C. Cobb, February 28, 1967. New York.
    Wray was born in 1926 and died in 2006.
  - Index to Names, 2 copies (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
  - Index to Subject Outlines, 2 copies (Box 27, Folder 3-4)